const propertiesofproteins = [ // overview and properties of proteins

]

const aminoacids = [ // Amino acids
{
question: "What are amino acids?",
answers: ["The building blocks of carbohydrates", "The building blocks of lipids", "The building blocks of proteins", "The building blocks of nucleic acids"],
correct: "The building blocks of proteins"
},       
{
question: "How many different naturally occurring amino acids are there in the human body?",
answers: ["10", "18", "21", "26"],
correct: "21"
},   
{
question: "Which part of the amino acid structure varies among different amino acids, giving each its unique properties?",
answers: ["Carboxyl group", "Amino group", "R-group (side chain)", "Hydrogen atom"],
correct: "R-group (side chain)"
},
{
question: "The sequence of amino acids in a protein is called:",
answers: ["Protein moity", "Amino acid chain", "Protein backbone", "Primary structure"],
correct: "Primary structure"
},
{
question: "Amino acids are joined together in a protein through which type of bond?",
answers: ["Ionic bond", "Hydrogen bond", "Peptide bond", "Covalent bond"],
correct: "Peptide bond"
},
{
question: "Which of the following is not one of the 20 standard amino acids used in protein synthesis?",
answers: ["Tryptophan", "Glucose", "Serine", "Valine"],
correct: "Glucose"
},
{
question: "Essential amino acids are:",
answers: ["Amino acids that are not necessary for the body", "Amino acids that the body can synthesize on its own", "Amino acids that must be obtained through the diet", "Amino acids found only in non-essential proteins"],
correct: "Amino acids that must be obtained through the diet"
},
{
question: "Which amino acid is known as the 'start' codon in protein synthesis?",
answers: ["Methionine", "Phenylalanine", "Leucine", "Lysine"],
correct: "Methionine"
},
{
question: "The three-dimensional shape of a protein, which is crucial for its function, is referred to as its:",
answers: ["Secondary structure", "Tertiary structure", "Quaternary structure", "Primary structure"],
correct: "Tertiary structure"
},
{
question: "Which property of amino acids allows them to act as buffers in biological systems?",
answers: ["Their R-groups", "Their amino groups", "Their carboxyl groups", "Their peptide bonds"],
correct: "Their carboxyl groups"
},
{
question: "How many conditionally-essential amino acids are there in the human body?",
answers: ["4", "6", "8", "10"],
correct: "6"
},
{
question: "Conditionally-essential amino acids are amino acids that:",
answers: ["Are only found in plant-based diets", "Must be obtained from dietary sources", "Become essential under certain circumstances or health conditions", "Are always essential for body functions"],
correct: "Become essential under certain circumstances or health conditions"
},
{
question: "Which of the following is a conditionally-essential amino acid that may become essential during times of illness or stress?",
answers: ["Valine", "Glutamine", "Serine", "Phenylalanine"],
correct: "Glutamine"
},
{
question: "Conditionally-essential amino acids are often required in increased amounts during:",
answers: ["Physical inactivity", "Intense exercise", "Normal growth and development", "Balanced diets"],
correct: "Intense exercise"
},
{
question: "When can an amino acid be considered conditionally-essential?",
answers: ["When it is never synthesized by the body", "When its synthesis is limited in the body under specific conditions", "When it is found in high quantities in the diet", "When it is only needed by athletes"],
correct: "When its synthesis is limited in the body under specific conditions"
},
{
question: "What type of bond is a peptide bond?",
answers: ["Ionic bond", "Hydrogen bond", "Covalent bond", "Van der Waals bond"],
correct: "Covalent bond"
},
{
question: "In the context of biochemistry, what does a peptide bond primarily connect?",
answers: ["Carbohydrates", "Nucleic acids", "Amino acids", "Lipids"],
correct: "Amino acids"
},
{
question: "Which functional groups are involved in the formation of a peptide bond?",
answers: ["Carboxyl and amino groups", "Methyl and hydroxyl groups", "Phosphate and sulfhydryl groups", "Aldehyde and ketone groups"],
correct: "Carboxyl and amino groups"
},
{
question: "What is the significance of a peptide bond in the structure of proteins?",
answers: ["It determines the protein's secondary structure.", "It is responsible for the protein's color.", "It forms the backbone of the protein and links amino acids.", "It regulates the protein's enzymatic activity."],
correct: "It forms the backbone of the protein and links amino acids."
},
{
question: "Which of the following bonds is NOT involved in the formation of a peptide bond?",
answers: ["Hydrogen bond", "Disulfide bond", "Peptide bond", "Covalent bond"],
correct: "Hydrogen bond"
},
{
question: "In a Fischer projection, the amino group of a D-amino acid is typically oriented to which side?",
answers: ["Left side", "Right side", "Top side", "Bottom side"],
correct: "Right side"
},
{
question: "Which term is commonly used to describe amino acids with their amino group on the right side in stereochemical representations?",
answers: ["L-amino acids", "R-amino acids", "D-amino acids", "S-amino acids"],
correct: "D-amino acids"
},
{
question: "What does the 'D' in D-amino acids stand for?",
answers: ["Dextro", "Levo", "Dexterous", "Levorotary"],
correct: "Dextro"
},
{
question: "The term 'D-amino acid' is used to specify the __________ of the amino group.",
answers: ["Size", "Color", "Stereochemistry", "Charge"],
correct: "Stereochemistry"
},
{
question: "Which type of amino acids is typically found in the proteins of most living organisms, including humans?",
answers: ["L-amino acids", "D-amino acids", "Both L and D-amino acids", "Neither L nor D-amino acids"],
correct: "L-amino acids"
},
{
question: "In an aqueous solution, how do amino acids typically exist?",
answers: ["As positively charged ions", "As negatively charged ions", "As dipolar ions or zwitterions", "As neutral molecules"],
correct: "As dipolar ions or zwitterions"
},
{
question: "What is a zwitterion?",
answers: ["A type of amino acid that lacks an amino group", "An amino acid with a net positive charge", "An amino acid with both a positive and a negative charge, canceling each other out", "An amino acid in its gaseous state"],
correct: "An amino acid with both a positive and a negative charge, canceling each other out"
},
{
question: "Which functional groups on an amino acid are responsible for the formation of a zwitterion?",
answers: ["Carboxyl group and amino group", "Hydroxyl group and sulfhydryl group", "Carbonyl group and phosphate group", "Methyl group and amine group"],
correct: "Carboxyl group and amino group"
},
{
question: "The presence of a zwitterion in amino acids makes them:",
answers: ["Highly reactive in solution", "Insoluble in water", "Electrically neutral overall", "Strong acids"],
correct: "Electrically neutral overall"
},
{
question: "Which term best describes the net charge of a zwitterion?",
answers: ["Positive", "Negative", "Neutral", "Variable"],
correct: "Neutral"
},
{
question: "What term is used to describe the relationship between D and L stereoisomer amino acids?",
answers: ["Diastereomers", "Epimers", "Enantiomers", "Isomers"],
correct: "Enantiomers"
},
{
question: "Enantiomers are stereoisomers that:",
answers: ["Have the same molecular formula", "Are mirror images of each other and cannot be superimposed", "Have different functional groups", "Are only found in living organisms"],
correct: "Are mirror images of each other and cannot be superimposed"
},
{
question: "In the context of amino acids, what property distinguishes D-amino acids from L-amino acids?",
answers: ["Their taste", "Their color", "The orientation of their amino groups", "The number of carbon atoms in their side chains"],
correct: "The orientation of their amino groups"
},
{
question: "Enantiomers have the same physical properties, except they differ in their:",
answers: ["Boiling points", "Density", "Optical activity", "Solubility"],
correct: "Optical activity"
},
{
question: "Which specific property is used to identify and distinguish enantiomers in the laboratory?",
answers: ["Their taste", "Their melting point", "Their specific rotation", "Their color"],
correct: "Their specific rotation"
},
{
question: "which portion of amino acid influence the solubility?",
answers: ["amine group", "carboxyl group", "hydrogen group", "side chain"],
correct: "side chain"
},
{
question: "Amino acids are considered diprotic acids because they can donate:",
answers: ["One proton in an aqueous solution", "Two protons in an aqueous solution", "Three protons in an aqueous solution", "Four protons in an aqueous solution"],
correct: "Two protons in an aqueous solution"
},
{
question: "Which of the following amino acids is classified as a hydrophobic, aliphatic amino acid?",
answers: ["Glutamine", "Arginine", "Alanine", "Serine"],
correct: "Alanine"
},
{
question: "Amino acids such as leucine, valine, and isoleucine, are characterized by having:",
answers: ["A sulfur atom in their side chains", "A branched aliphatic side chain", "A polar and charged side chain", "No side chain"],
correct: "A branched aliphatic side chain"
},
{
question: "Which of the following amino acids is known for its branched aliphatic side chain and is commonly found in proteins involved in muscle metabolism?",
answers: ["Glycine", "Methionine", "Leucine", "Lysine"],
correct: "Leucine"
},
{
question: "Hydrophobic amino acids tend to be repelled by water due to their:",
answers: ["Strong ionic interactions with water molecules", "Ability to form hydrogen bonds with water", "Nonpolar nature and weak interactions with water", "High solubility in water"],
correct: "Nonpolar nature and weak interactions with water"
},
{
question: "Which hydrophobic amino acid is unique in its structure, containing a sulfur atom in its side chain, and is often involved in the initiation of protein synthesis?",
answers: ["Isoleucine", "Methionine", "Proline", "Alanine"],
correct: "Methionine"
}, 
{
question: "Among the listed amino acids, which one is unique for its cyclic structure and often disrupts the secondary structure of proteins?",
answers: ["Valine", "Glycine", "Proline", "Isoleucine"],
correct: "Proline"
},
{
question: "Which functional group is found in the side chain of the amino acid methionine?",
answers: ["Thioester group", "Carboxyl group", "Hydroxyl group", "Amine group"],
correct: "Thioester group"
}, 
{
question: "Methionine is known for its role in protein synthesis as the initiating amino acid. What is the significance of the thioester group in this context?",
answers: ["It forms peptide bonds between amino acids.", "It provides a source of energy for protein synthesis.", "It enhances the color of the protein.", "It determines the amino acid's taste."],
correct: "It provides a source of energy for protein synthesis."
},
{
question: "Thioester bonds are involved in various biological processes. Which one of the following processes typically involves thioester bonds?",
answers: ["Photosynthesis", "DNA replication", "Cellular respiration", "Protein folding"],
correct: "DNA replication"
},
{
question: "The thioester group in methionine consists of a sulfur atom bonded to which other atom or group?",
answers: ["Nitrogen", "Oxygen", "Carbon", "Hydrogen"],
correct: "Carbon"
},
{
question: "In addition to its role in protein synthesis, methionine is also important for:",
answers: ["Storing genetic information", "Acting as a neurotransmitter", "Participating in the one-carbon metabolism pathway", "Regulating pH in the stomach"],
correct: "Participating in the one-carbon metabolism pathway"
},
{
question: "Thioester bonds, like those in methionine, are commonly found in molecules involved in energy transfer and storage. Which molecule utilizes thioester bonds to store and transfer chemical energy in biological systems?",
answers: ["Adenosine triphosphate (ATP)", "Water (H2O)", "Carbon dioxide (CO2)", "Oxygen (O2)"],
correct: "Adenosine triphosphate (ATP)"
},
{
question: "Which amino acid is the simplest in structure and is formally classified as hydrophobic but cannot actively contribute to hydrophobic interactions?",
answers: ["Valine", "Leucine", "Glycine", "Methionine"],
correct: "Glycine"
},
{
question: "Glycine is unique among amino acids because it lacks a side chain or R-group, which typically plays a significant role in determining an amino acid's properties. What is the result of this lack of a side chain in glycine?",
answers: ["Glycine is highly hydrophobic.", "Glycine is highly hydrophilic.", "Glycine has a net positive charge.", "Glycine cannot form peptide bonds."],
correct: "Glycine is highly hydrophilic."
},
{
question: "Despite being formally classified as hydrophobic, glycine is often considered hydrophilic due to its:",
answers: ["Aliphatic side chain", "Polar and charged side chain", "Lack of side chain", "Branched side chain"],
correct: "Lack of side chain"
},
{
question: "Hydrophobic interactions in proteins are crucial for protein folding and stability. Why is glycine unable to actively participate in these interactions?",
answers: ["Glycine is positively charged.", "Glycine lacks a side chain, limiting its hydrophobic character.", "Glycine is involved in ionic interactions with other amino acids.", "Glycine is only found in nonpolar regions of proteins."],
correct: "Glycine lacks a side chain, limiting its hydrophobic character."
},
{
question: "Glycine is often found in the structure of collagen, a fibrous protein. In this context, what role does glycine play?",
answers: ["It provides color to collagen.", "It imparts a strong odor to collagen.", "It forms a repeating structure and contributes to collagen's strength.", "It regulates the solubility of collagen."],
correct: "It forms a repeating structure and contributes to collagen's strength."
},
{
question: "Which amino acids are classified as aromatic and hydrophobic due to the presence of an aromatic ring in their side chains?",
answers: ["Histidine, serine, and aspartic acid", "Glycine, leucine, and arginine", "Tryptophan, tyrosine, and phenylalanine", "Lysine, proline, and glutamine"],
correct: "Tryptophan, tyrosine, and phenylalanine"
},
{
question: "The aromatic side chains of tryptophan, tyrosine, and phenylalanine are known to contribute to the structural stability of proteins through:",
answers: ["Forming disulfide bridges", "Participating in ionic interactions", "Creating hydrophobic interactions", "Promoting hydrogen bonding"],
correct: "Creating hydrophobic interactions"
},
{
question: "Among the aromatic hydrophobic amino acids, which one is involved in the synthesis of important neurotransmitters, such as dopamine and epinephrine?",
answers: ["Tryptophan", "Tyrosine", "Phenylalanine", "Methionine"],
correct: "Tyrosine"
},
{
question: "The aromatic ring in tyrosine and phenylalanine contains which element in its structure?",
answers: ["Sulfur", "Oxygen", "Nitrogen", "Carbon"],
correct: "Carbon"
},
{
question: "Aromatic amino acids are often found in the active sites of enzymes involved in catalyzing reactions. Which of these amino acids plays a crucial role in the active sites of enzymes due to its versatile side chain interactions?",
answers: ["Tryptophan", "Tyrosine", "Phenylalanine", "Arginine"],
correct: "Tyrosine"
},
{
question: "Which statement accurately describes the structure of tryptophan?",
answers: ["Tryptophan has a hydroxyl group in its side chain.", "Tryptophan contains a nitrogen atom in its indole ring.", "Tryptophan is slightly more polar than tyrosine and phenylalanine.", "Tryptophan lacks an aromatic ring in its side chain."],
correct: "Tryptophan contains a nitrogen atom in its indole ring."
},
{
question: "Among tryptophan, tyrosine, and phenylalanine, which amino acid contains a hydroxyl (OH) group in its side chain?",
answers: ["Tryptophan", "Tyrosine", "Phenylalanine", "All of the above"],
correct: "Tyrosine"
},
{
question: "What is the distinctive feature of tyrosine's side chain that sets it apart from the other two aromatic amino acids?",
answers: ["It contains an aromatic ring.", "It is nonpolar.", "It has a nitrogen atom in its indole ring.", "It includes a hydroxyl group."],
correct: "It includes a hydroxyl group."
},
{
question: "Phenylalanine is slightly more polar than tyrosine and tryptophan. What specific property contributes to this increased polarity?",
answers: ["Its ability to form disulfide bonds", "The presence of a sulfur atom in its side chain", "The presence of a nitrogen atom in its indole ring", "The absence of a hydroxyl group in its side chain."],
correct: "The absence of a hydroxyl group in its side chain."
},
{
question: "Which of the following amino acids is classified as a polar, uncharged amino acid and contains a hydroxyl group in its side chain?",
answers: ["Serine and Threonine", "Cysteine and Cystine", "Asparagine and Glutamine", "Glutamine and Cystine"],
correct: "Serine and Threonine"
},
{
question: "Serine and threonine both share a common functional group in their side chains. What is this functional group?",
answers: ["Amino group", "Carboxyl group", "Sulfhydryl group", "Hydroxyl group", "Amino group", "Imidazole group"],
correct: "Hydroxyl group"
},
{
question: "Cysteine is known for its ability to form disulfide bonds, contributing to the stability of protein structures. What element is involved in the formation of these bonds?",
answers: ["Nitrogen", "Oxygen", "Sulfur", "Carbon", "Phosphorus", "Fluorine"],
correct: "Sulfur"
},
{
question: "Asparagine and glutamine are polar, uncharged amino acids that contain which functional group in their side chains?",
answers: ["Carboxyl group", "Hydroxyl group", "Amino group", "Amide group", "Sulfhydryl group", "Imidazole group"],
correct: "Amide group"
},
{
question: "Cystine, often formed by the oxidation of cysteine residues, is a dimeric amino acid. What type of bond links the two cysteine molecules in cystine?",
answers: ["Peptide bond", "Disulfide bond", "Hydrogen bond", "Ionic bond", "Covalent bond", "Ester bond"],
correct: "Disulfide bond"
},
{
question: "Which statement is correct?",
answers: ["two cystine residue form cysteine", "two cysteine residue form cystine", "cystine residue oxidize to form cysteine", "none of the above"],
correct: "two cysteine residue form cystine"
},
{
question: "Which have aromatic side chain?",
answers: ["Serine", "Tyrosine", "Alanine", "Glycine"],
correct: "Tyrosine"
},
{
question: "Tryptophan is?",
answers: ["Hydrophilic, aliphatic", "Hydrophobic, aliphatic", "Hydrophobic, aromatic", "Hydrophilic, aromatic"],
correct: "Hydrophobic, aromatic"
},
{
question: "Phenylalanine is?",
answers: ["Hydrophilic, aliphatic", "Hydrophobic, aliphatic", "Hydrophobic, aromatic", "Hydrophilic, aromatic"],
correct: "Hydrophobic, aromatic"
},
{
question: "Tyrosine is?",
answers: ["Hydrophilic, aliphatic", "Hydrophobic, aliphatic", "Hydrophobic, aromatic", "Hydrophilic, aromatic"],
correct: "Hydrophobic, aromatic"
},
{
question: "Cystine is",
answers: ["Polar", "Non-polar", "aliphatic", "aromatic"],
correct: "Non-polar"
},
{
question: "Two polar cysteine molecule is joined by ___ to form non polar cystine",
answers: ["disulfide bond", "peptide bond", "glycosidic bond", "amide bond"],
correct: "disulfide bond"
},
{
question: "Dimeric amino acid is which of the following?",
answers: ["Cysteine", "Cystine", "Glycine", "Glutamine"],
correct: "Cystine"
},
{
question: "Asparagine is derived from which amino acid through the addition of an amide group in its side chain?",
answers: ["Aspartate", "Glutamine", "Cysteine", "Phenylalanine"],
correct: "Aspartate"
},
{
question: "Glutamine is formed from which amino acid by the addition of an amide group to its side chain?",
answers: ["Glutamate", "Lysine", "Tyrosine", "Arginine"],
correct: "Glutamate"
},
{
question: "The amide group in asparagine and glutamine contains which element?",
answers: ["Oxygen", "Nitrogen", "Carbon", "Hydrogen"],
correct: "Nitrogen"
},
{
question: "Aspartate and glutamate are considered acidic amino acids due to the presence of a carboxyl group in their side chains. What functional group distinguishes asparagine and glutamine from their acidic counterparts?",
answers: ["Hydroxyl group", "Amino group", "Sulfhydryl group", "Imidazole group"],
correct: "Amino group"
},
{
question: "The amide groups in asparagine and glutamine are important for various biological processes, including the formation of peptide bonds during protein synthesis. What role does the amide group play in this context?",
answers: ["It acts as a catalyst in peptide bond formation.", "It provides color to proteins.", "It facilitates disulfide bond formation.", "It acts as an antioxidant."],
correct: "It acts as a catalyst in peptide bond formation."
},
{
question: "Which group of amino acids is characterized by having a positive charge at physiological pH and is often involved in binding negatively charged molecules in biological processes?",
answers: ["Hydrophobic amino acids", "Polar, positive charge amino acids", "Aromatic amino acids", "Aliphatic amino acids"],
correct: "Polar, positive charge amino acids"
},
{
question: "Among lysine, arginine, and histidine, which amino acid is known for having a long aliphatic side chain that contains a primary amine group?",
answers: ["Lysine", "Arginine", "Histidine", "All three have similar side chains"],
correct: "Lysine"
},
{
question: "The positive charge in lysine, arginine, and histidine is attributed to the presence of which functional group in their side chains?",
answers: ["Carboxyl group", "Amino group", "Hydroxyl group", "Sulfhydryl group"],
correct: "Amino group"
},
{
question: "Histidine plays a crucial role in enzyme catalysis and is often involved in acid-base reactions due to its ability to act as both a proton donor and a proton acceptor. This property is known as:",
answers: ["Zwitterion formation", "Buffering capacity", "Hydrogen bonding", "Hydrophobic interaction"],
correct: "Buffering capacity"
},
{
question: "Lysine, arginine, and histidine are often found in the active sites of enzymes and are involved in interactions with nucleic acids and other negatively charged molecules. This characteristic is essential for which biological process?",
answers: ["Photosynthesis", "DNA replication", "Cellular respiration", "Protein folding"],
correct: "DNA replication"
},
{
question: "Which amino acid is unique among the standard 20 amino acids because it possesses a second amino group at the sigma carbon of its side chain?",
answers: ["Aspartate", "Arginine", "Glycine", "Lysine"],
correct: "Lysine"
},
{
question: "The second amino group in lysine's side chain allows it to form what type of bond with adjacent amino acids in a protein's primary structure?",
answers: ["Peptide bond", "Disulfide bond", "Hydrogen bond", "Ionic bond"],
correct: "Peptide bond"
},
{
question: "Lysine is often involved in interactions with negatively charged molecules such as DNA and RNA. What role does the second amino group in its side chain play in these interactions?",
answers: ["It forms hydrogen bonds with DNA and RNA.", "It repels negatively charged molecules.", "It participates in covalent bonding with DNA and RNA.", "It provides color to DNA and RNA."],
correct: "It forms hydrogen bonds with DNA and RNA."
},
{
question: "Lysine's ability to form peptide bonds and interact with nucleic acids is crucial for various biological processes, including:",
answers: ["Oxygen transport in blood", "Muscle contraction", "Enzyme regulation", "Genetic information storage and protein synthesis"],
correct: "Genetic information storage and protein synthesis"
},
{
question: "Which of the following amino acids is characterized by having a positively charged guanidino group in its side chain?",
answers: ["Asparagine", "Glutamine", "Arginine", "Lysine"],
correct: "Arginine"
},
{
question: "Arginine's guanidino group is positively charged at physiological pH. This positive charge allows arginine to participate in which type of interaction with negatively charged molecules?",
answers: ["Hydrogen bonding", "Hydrophobic interactions", "Van der Waals forces", "Ionic interactions"],
correct: "Ionic interactions"
},
{
question: "Histidine is unique among amino acids because it contains an imidazole group in its side chain. This group can act as both a proton donor and a proton acceptor, making histidine an important component of enzyme active sites. This property is known as:",
answers: ["Buffering capacity", "Hydrophobic interaction", "Peptide bonding", "Allosteric regulation"],
correct: "Buffering capacity"
},
{
question: "The imidazole group in histidine can serve as a proton shuttle in catalytic reactions. What role does it play in enzymatic reactions?",
answers: ["It forms disulfide bonds.", "It acts as a reducing agent.", "It participates in covalent bonding with substrates.", "It facilitates the transfer of protons between molecules."],
correct: "It facilitates the transfer of protons between molecules."
},
{
question: "The presence of arginine and histidine in enzyme active sites allows them to interact with substrates through various mechanisms, including electrostatic interactions and proton transfer. These interactions are crucial for the efficiency of which biological processes?",
answers: ["Photosynthesis", "DNA replication", "Cellular respiration", "Enzyme-catalyzed reactions"],
correct: "Enzyme-catalyzed reactions"
},
{
question: "Which group of amino acids is characterized by having a negative charge at physiological pH and is often involved in electrostatic interactions with positively charged molecules?",
answers: ["Hydrophobic amino acids", "Polar, negative charge amino acids", "Aromatic amino acids", "Aliphatic amino acids"],
correct: "Polar, negative charge amino acids"
},
{
question: "Among aspartate and glutamate, which amino acid is known for having a carboxyl group in its side chain, contributing to its negative charge?",
answers: ["Aspartate", "Glutamate", "Cysteine", "Tyrosine"],
correct: "Aspartate"
},
{
question: "The negative charge in aspartate and glutamate is attributed to the presence of which functional group in their side chains?",
answers: ["Carboxyl group", "Amino group", "Hydroxyl group", "Sulfhydryl group"],
correct: "Carboxyl group"
},
{
question: "Aspartate and glutamate are often involved in ionic interactions with positively charged amino acids like lysine and arginine. What type of bond forms between the positively charged and negatively charged amino acids in these interactions?",
answers: ["Hydrogen bond", "Disulfide bond", "Ionic bond", "Covalent bond"],
correct: "Ionic bond"
},
{
question: "Aspartate and glutamate play essential roles in cellular processes, including enzyme regulation and signal transduction. Their negative charge allows them to interact with positively charged ions. What is a common positively charged ion that they interact with?",
answers: ["Calcium (Ca2+)", "Sodium (Na+)", "Potassium (K+)", "Magnesium (Mg2+)"],
correct: "Calcium (Ca2+)"
}, 
{
question: "What is the relationship between asparagine and aspartate?",
answers: ["no relationship.", "Asparagine is an amide of aspartate.", "Aspartate is a precursor of asparagine.", "Aspartate is an amide of asparagine."],
correct: "Aspartate is an amide of asparagine."
},
{
question: "How is glutamine related to glutamate?",
answers: ["no relationship.", "Glutamate is a precursor of glutamine.", "Glutamine is an amide of glutamate.", "Glutamate is an amide of glutamine."],
correct: "Glutamine is an amide of glutamate."
},
{
question: "What enzymatic process is responsible for the conversion of glutamate to glutamine?",
answers: ["Amidation", "Deamination", "Oxidation", "Hydrolysis"],
correct: "Amidation"
},
{
question: "Which of the following amino acids are sulfur-containing amino acids?",
answers: ["Alanine and proline", "Lysine and phenylalanine", "Methionine and cysteine", "Glutamine and aspartate"],
correct: "Methionine and cysteine"
},
{
question: "Methionine is unique among the sulfur-containing amino acids because it is the precursor for the synthesis of which important molecule?",
answers: ["Hemoglobin", "DNA", "Fatty acids", "S-adenosylmethionine (SAM)"],
correct: "S-adenosylmethionine (SAM)"
},
{
question: "Cysteine contains a thiol group (-SH) in its side chain, which allows it to form what type of chemical bond that is crucial for protein structure and stability?",
answers: ["Disulfide bond", "Hydrogen bond", "Ionic bond", "Covalent bond"],
correct: "Disulfide bond"
},
{
question: "Methionine is often the initiating amino acid in the synthesis of proteins. It provides the start codon with the necessary amino group. Which start codon does it pair with in mRNA?",
answers: ["AUG", "UAA", "UAG", "UGA"],
correct: "AUG"
},
{
question: "Which of the following sulfur-containing amino acids is commonly involved in the formation of disulfide bridges within and between proteins, contributing to their structural stability?",
answers: ["Methionine", "Cysteine", "Tryptophan", "Arginine"],
correct: "Cysteine"
},
{
question: "An amino acid that yields acetoacetyl-CoA during the catabolism",
answers: ["Glycogenic", "Ketogenic", "Both glycogenic and ketogenic", "Essential"],
correct: "Ketogenic"
},
{
question: "Which among the following is both glucogenic and ketogenic?",
answers: ["Isoleucine", "Leucine", "Lysine", "Histidine"],
correct: "Isoleucine"
},
{
question: "Which of the following is an essential amino acid?",
answers: ["Cysteine", "Asparagine", "Glutamine", "Phenylalanine"],
correct: "Phenylalanine"
},
{
question: "  Which among the following  is a non-essential amino acids?",
answers: ["Serine", "Threonine", "Lysine", "Histidine"],
correct: "Serine"
},
{
question: "Absorbance at 280nm exhibited by protein is due to",
answers: ["aliphatic amino acids", "all amino acids", "non-polar amino acids", "aromatic amino acids"],
correct: "aromatic amino acids"
},
{
question: "Positively charged basic amino acids are",
answers: ["Lysine and arginine", "Lysine and asparagine", "Glutamine and arginine", "Lysine and glutamine"],
correct: "Lysine and arginine"
},
           
          
]
const peptides = [ // Peptides
   
]